# Alim Satria Fi'i Wijaya Kusuma

HARDWARE ENGINEER · PCB DESIGNER

Sleman Regency, Yogyakarta, Indonesia

🗷 alimsatria45@outlook.com | 😭 justraven.github.io/portfolio | 🖸 github.com/justraven | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/alimsatria

#### **Personal Profile**

A student at Universitas Gadjah Mada specializing in Instrumentation and Control Engineering Technology with a strong passion for Control Systems and Hardware Engineering. I am actively engage in diverse projects related to instrumentation and control systems, including coding microcontrollers, designing PCBs, and documenting projects using LaTeX and GitHub.

#### **Education**

**Universitas Gadjah Mada** 

Yoqyakarta, Indonesia

Undergraduate degree in Instrumentation and Control Engineering Technology

2021 - Current

**Universitas Gadjah Mada** 

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Associate degree in Instrumentation Technology

2017 - 2021

### Work Experience\_

#### PT. Integrasi Teknologi Unggas (BroilerX)

Yoqyakarta, Indonesia

Hardware Engineer

Jan 2021 - Mar 2022

- Developed an IoT devices to monitor the environment of broiler house.
- Responsible for the PCB design process, creating prototypes, communicating and collaborating on IoT integration in the device, and ensuring the device operates effectively.
- Technical Skills: PCB Design using KiCAD, Firmware programming using C++, Internet of Things
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication.

## **University Projects**

#### Implementation of Flight Controller Design and PID Control on Quadrotor Attitude

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Gadjah Mada - Undergraduate

Dec 2022 - Current

- Make and iterate PCB design of quadrotor flight controller to find the most compact and stable design using 8-bit microcontroller
- Tuning and refining the quadrotor attitude control using PID to make a stable attitude control and add feature to the program to log the IMU sensor and GPS data
- Technical skill: PCB design using KiCAD, Programinng in Processing 2 (Java), control system

#### Remake of Feedback ES151

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Gadjah Mada - Undergraduate

Dec 2022

- I have undertaken the project of reviving and repairing an old Feedback ES151 system to make it suitable for learning and demonstrating PID control for velocity and position of a DC motor. Additionally, I am designing a Human-Machine Interface (HMI) using LabView, which will enable the machine to interact with and be controlled through a computer interface.
- Code the microcontroller using C++ and bridge the communication between the computer (HMI) and the machine
- Technical skill: Programming in C++, Building HMI with LabVIEW

# Design and Implementation of Light Ambient Control System on Broiler Farm Using PID Controller

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Gadjah Mada - Assosiate

2020

- I am working on the development of a device that aims to maintain a consistent level of light intensity within broiler chicken cages. This device utilizes a microcontroller connected to a light sensor and an LED. Additionally, I am designing a Human-Machine Interface (HMI) using LabVIEW. The device is capable of interacting with and being controlled through a web application that is accessible over the internet.
- Technical skill: PCB Design using EAGLE, Firmware programming using C++, HMI Programming using LabVIEW

#### Skills

Programming

Python, LabView, C, C++, Matlab.

**Hardware Design** 

Kicad, Eagle

**Soft Skills** 

Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation.

JUNE 20, 2023

#### Interests\_

#### Linux

Since 2017, I developed a deep affection for Linux, which I utilize extensively for coding and hardware design purposes. My preferred distribution is KDE Neon due to its visually appealing interface.

#### **Technical Writing**

I have documented several projects related to control systems and hardware design on my GitHub profile. One project that stands out as a personal favorite is the revival of an old PID tuning machine for the control system lab. For this project, I created the Human-Machine Interface (HMI) using LabView and wrote the main controller code in C++. I invite you to explore the project documentation by following this <u>link</u>.

LaTeX

I have a strong appreciation for using LaTeX to compose my lab reports, as it allows me to create visually appealing, stylish, and well-organized documents. I have even taken the initiative to develop a lab report template. Feel free to explore my template by visiting this <u>link</u>.

### Languages\_

**English** Professional proficiency (TOEFL ITP Score : 567/677)

IndonesianNative proficiencyJavaneseNative proficiency